# Colton Kaiser

Seattle, WA (Willing to relocate) | 480-229-1745 | kaiserc2@seattleu.edu | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/coltonkaiser Portfolio: coltonkaiser.dev | GitHub: github.com/ckaiser258 | Blog: medium.com/@coltonkaiser

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Full-stack software engineer with five years of experience in strength and conditioning. My education and experience provide me with strong analytical skills and a systems-driven mindset which informs my coding. I am excited to combine my leadership skills with my software engineering expertise to contribute to an organization that values professionalism, collaboration, and offers a rich environment for constant growth and improvement.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

ReactJS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, OO Design, RESTful APIs, Postgres, HTML/CSS HackerRank React Certified, HackerRank JavaScript Certified

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Performance Mapper - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

An athletic performance monitoring tool that allows strength and conditioning coaches to monitor the performance and injury trends of their teams/athletes

- Used ReactJS, React Bootstrap, and Material UI for the frontend user experience
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Created a Rails backend with BCrypt to allow users to securely store, access, and modify their information
- Used React ChartJS to display recorded subjective data for individual athletes as well as objective trends in performance and injuries throughout the user's teams

#### Movie Shelf - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

An app that allows a user to add their favorite movies to a personal shelf and view information about each

- Developed an app that allows users to search for movies, view information and add, edit, and delete each one. Collaborated with a team of programmers
- Utilized the OMDB API to allow a user to search through thousands of movies and be provided information on each
- Created a Rails backend for the user to store their respective movies
- Used ReactJS along with React Bootstrap to create an efficient user experience
- Created POST, PATCH, and DELETE request for full CRUD functionality

## VisionBoard - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

A goal monitoring tool that allows users to keep track of and customize personal and professional goals

- Programmed an app that allows users to sign up, create boards, and add goals to their respective boards along with CRUD operations for each. Collaborated with a team of four programmers
- Used a Rails backend to store new users and boards/goals saved by the user
- Used vanilla Javascript to set up event handling and increase user interaction capabilities
- Styled and structured the app with HTML and CSS

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School Seattle, WA 04/2020 - 08/2020

Full Stack Software Development, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Seattle, WA

Seattle University M.A. in Sports Administration & Leadership (3.7 GPA)

06/2019

**Arizona State University** B.S. in Exercise Science

Phoenix, AZ 06/2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Vigor Ground Performance**

Head of Sports Performance

Seattle, WA 07/2019-04/2020

- Was in a leadership position for a department dedicated to growing the business and revenue for a target population
- Created and lead athletic performance programs built through systematic progressions and regular testing
- Collaborated and built rapport with sport coaches and athletic trainers to achieve a common goal for each team/athlete, and use problem-solving along the way
- Gained public speaking and organizational skills by creating and leading seminars
- Provided leadership, education and management for groups of interns

#### Seattle Professional Rugby

Injured Players Coordinator

Seattle, WA 02/2019 - 06/2019

- Programmed, scheduled, and coached all long-term injured players for return to play
- Created return-to-play programs with a heavy emphasis on injury analysis and rehab procedures
- Learned data collection and utilization to monitor performance/workload and program accordingly

# **Seattle University**

Graduate Assistant Strength and Conditioning Coach

Seattle, WA 06/2017 - 08/2019

- Utilized leadership and time-management skills to program and implemented strength, speed, and conditioning programs for over 120 athletes
- Maintained a systematic yet flexible approach to sports performance and injury prevention through the use of performance data collection and movement analysis
- Collaborated with sport coaches and athletic trainers to ensure an integrated system for athletic performance enhancement
- Created and fostered a team environment that is challenging, motivating and conducive to growth

#### Florida International University

Strength and Conditioning Intern

Miami, FL 06/2018 - 08/2018

- Assisted with the coaching & implementation of the summer strength, speed, conditioning, & injury prevention program for over 100 football athletes and six other teams
- Gained experience learning to program for a very large and diverse group of athletes
- Completed a full and comprehensive intern education curriculum covering all aspects of sports performance as well as career management
- Pushed through discomfort and adapted to a high-pressure environment

### **University of Denver**

Sports Performance Intern

Denver, CO 01/2017 - 05/2017

- Assisted coaches with the implementation of strength & conditioning programs, injury rehab and data collection for all 17 sports
- Gained unique experience related to evidence-based training, 3D evaluation techniques and knowledge related to functional applied science
- Was challenged to learn and grow while working 12 hour days

# **Center for Athletic Performance**

Sports Performance Specialist

Scottsdale, AZ 09/2016 - 12/2016

- Programmed strength, power, conditioning, speed, agility and injury prevention for multiple different teams while utilizing performance testing and systematic processes
- Was tasked with diverse coaching and programming, and rapport-building to fit the needs of a wide variety of athletes and populations